Lawrence Clark Powell papers, 1890-2001 (bulk, 1971-1991)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Lawrence Clark Powell papers, 1890-2001 (bulk, 1971-1991)
MS 376
Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-2001
Collection consists primarily of files maintained by Lawrence Clark Powell during his residency in Tucson and his tenure at the University of Arizona. Includes correspondence, research files, transcripts of talks, and manuscripts of a variety of books and articles. Much of the collection documents his activities at the University of Arizona, as well as writings he completed during the 1970s and 1980s. Selected correspondents include Edward Abbey, Ansel Adams, Bruce Babbitt, and Paul Horgan. Most of the collection is maintained in the original order in which the files were kept by Powell.
18 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Lawrence Clark Powell was a noted writer and librarian. Powell was well-known for his writings on librarianship and the literature of the American Southwest, including books such as Books West Southwest and Southwest Classics. He served as head librarian at UCLA from 1944 to 1961, when he became the founding dean of the UCLA Graduate School of Library Service. After retiring from UCLA, Powell moved to Tucson, Arizona in 1971, where he served as a Professor in Residence at the University of Arizona's newly-established Graduate School of Library Science. He played a major role in the development of the School as well as the University of Arizona Library until the late 1980s. Powell died in Tucson on March 14, 2001 at the age of 94.
Organization
This collection is organized into fifteen series:
I. Biographical Materials, 1976-2001
II. Personal Files, 1950-1991
III. University of Arizona Files, 1965-1991
IV. Authors and Southwest Classics Files, 1890-1990
V. Southwest Classics Book, 1972-1975
VI. "Letters from the Southwest" Column, 1969-1980
VII. Arizona Highways, 1975-1979
VIII. Photographs of the Southwest, 1975-1989
IX. Where Water Flows, 1978-1981
X. River Articles and Files, 1946-1989
XI. Arizona: A Bicentennial History, 1954-1987
XII. Mysterious Transformation, 1992
XIII. Book Catalogs, 1950-1982
XIV. Video and Audio Tapes, 1976-1989
XV. Awards, 1976-1989
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists primarily of files maintained by Lawrence Clark Powell during his residency in Tucson and his tenure at the University of Arizona. Includes correspondence, research files, transcripts of talks, and manuscripts of a variety of books and articles. Much of the collection documents his activities at the University of Arizona, as well as writings he completed during the 1970s and 1980s. Selected correspondents include Edward Abbey, Ansel Adams, Bruce Babbitt, and Paul Horgan. Most of the collection is maintained in the original order in which the files were kept by Powell.
Access Terms
Abbey, Edward, 1927- -- Correspondence.
Adams, Ansel, 1902- -- Correspondence.
Babbitt, Bruce E. -- Correspondence.
Horgan, Paul, 1903- -- Correspondence.
American literature -- Southwest, New -- History and criticism
Authors, American -- 20th century
Librarians -- United States -- 20th century
Arizona -- History
University of Arizona. Library -- History
Container List
- Series I: Biographical Materials, 1976-2001
  - Biographical materials. 1976-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Personal Files, 1950-1991
  - "A". 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, John Houghton. 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arizona and the West. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Arts Commission Awards. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Bicentennial Book Supplement. 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arizona Environment Talk and other Materials. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arizona Environment Talk. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arizona Environment Talk. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arizona Environment Talk. 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arizona Heritage (book proposal). No date (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arizona Highway Committee. 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arizona Highways, Mark Sanders. 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arizona Highways. 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arizona Highways, Meyer and Ring Report. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arizona Historical Society. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arizona Historical Conference. 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - UA Talk "A Cold Look at a Hot Subject". 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arizona Literary Trails (talks and articles). 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ASU Talk "Readin', Writin', and Collectin'". 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ASU Talk "Art in Life, Life in Art". 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ASU Talk. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Articles by Lawrence Clark Powell. 1919-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Arizona State Library Association Talk. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Arizona State Library Association Committee on Arizona Author Award. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Sonora Desert Museum. 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "B". 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Babbitt, Bruce (Pt. 1). 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Babbitt, Bruce (Pt. 2). 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Barton, Paul. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bicentennial Talks. 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bowden, Charles (Pt. 1). 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bowden, Charles (Pt. 2). 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brown, J.P.S. 1970-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Talk on J.P.S. Brown, NMSU. 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bullock, Wynn. 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bundy, Winn. 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bundy, Robert. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "C". 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Center for the Book (includes talk "Next to Mother's Milk…"). 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cheek, Larry. 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Colonial Dames Talk. 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Colorado Library Association Talk "The Long Commitment". 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cottonwood Referendum. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Tucson Cultural Center. 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "D". 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - UA Talk "Dark Spring, Bright Spring". 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Desert as Dwelled Upon. 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Talks to Society for History and Discoveries. 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "E'". 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Talk "Great Constellations" at El Paso, Meeting of New Mexico and Texas State Library Associations. 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Talk "Extra Dimension" Sigma Xi, University of Arizona. 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "F". 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Farah, Cynthia (includes photographs of LCP). 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Preface to Bert Fireman's Arizona: Historic Land. 1968-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fireman, Bert. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Talk "Angles of Vision" at Flagstaff, Southwest Writers Conference. 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fontana, Bunny (Pt.1). 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fontana, Bunny (Pt.2). 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "G". 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Green Valley. 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "H". 1970-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hanley, T.E. 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hinchiff, Bill. 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Honeymann, R.B. 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - UA Honors Convocation Talk. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Talk "Home is…" to American Association of Housing Educators. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hyde, Philip. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - UT-Austin Humanities Research Center. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - UA Commencement Talk "A Hunger for Heroes". 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hoffman, Richard. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Invitations and Keepsakes. 1950-1996 (Box 4, Folder 12a)
  - "J". No date, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - James, George Wharton. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "K". 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kino, Eusebio. 1936-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "L". 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Laird, David, Arizona Guidebook. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Land of Many Returns" Article. 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - UA Library School Colloquium. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Lion in the Desert" Interview. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Lowman, Al (Pt. 1). 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Lowman, Al (Pt. 2). 1980-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "M". 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Mc". 1983-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - UA Library Map Collection. 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Martin, Paul (LCP talk on Van Dyke at Tumamoc Hill). 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Maxwell, Margaret (Pt. 1). 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Maxwell, Margaret (Pt. 2). 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities. 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Talk "Rivers Determine" National Historical Society Conference, Santa Fe. 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Talk "Sex and Success in the Southwest Novel" New Mexico Historical Society Conference, Santa Fe. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Talk "When Does History Become Literature?" New Mexico Historical Society Conference, Las Vegas. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Talk "Trailing Literature Through the Southwest" New Mexico Library Association Conference, Albuquerque. 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Spell of New Mexico (includes essay by Jack Rittenhouse). 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - New Mexico Book League. 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Storied New Mexico. 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - From the Heartland, Northland Press. 1975-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of From the Heartland, Northland Press. 1977-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Where Water Flows, Northland Press. 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reviews of Where Water Flows, Northland Press. 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Northland Press Study. 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nusser, Charlotte. No date (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Olch, Peter. 1984-1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Oracle: A Voluntary of Poems and Prints. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Overland Book Shop. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "P". 1982-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Palm Springs. 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Perceval, Don. 1957-1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Phi Beta Kappa. 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Talk "These Things are Priceless" Arizona Faculty Legislator Conference, Phoenix. 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Talk "Beyond the Bicentennial" The First Century Conference, Phoenix. 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Polzer, Charles. 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Talk "Books Determine" Friends of Prescott Public Library. 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "R". 1985-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Regrets (invitations declined). 1981-1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Research Library Resources Class. 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Research Library Resources Class. 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rincon High School Talk. 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Rosenzweig Award from Arizona State Library Association. 1975-1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "S' (Pt. 1). 1968-1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "S' (Pt. 2). 1985-1989 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Santa Fe. 1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Talk "My New Mexico Literary Friends" Book Arts Festival, Santa Fe. 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Schaefer, John. 1975-1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Schaefer, John, Photography (includes photographs of Shiprock, and LCP). 1977-1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Simmons, Marc (Pt. 1). 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Simmons, Marc (Pt. 2). 1981-1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sobin, Harris. 1960-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Talk "Water-There Ought to be a Law" Sonoran Heritage Project. 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - University of Arizona Southwest Center. 1982-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Southwest Review 1956-1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Voices from the Southwest (includes several photographs). 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Southwest Classics. 1982-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Southwest Literature and Libraries Course. 1962-1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Southwest Book Trails. 1963-1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Talk "A Way of Life" University of South Carolina (includes photographs). 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - University of Arizona Library Special Collections. 1972-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Talk to Special Libraries Association. 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Speech, St. Gregory High School, Tucson. 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Daily Star Christmas List. 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stoffle, Carla. 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Talk "Arizona River Trails" Sunday Evening Forum, Green Valley. 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Talk "Number 2" Arizona Superintendents Meeting, Tucson. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "T". 1984-1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Talk "Thunder at Your Back" Phi Kappa Phi and Gamma Sigma Delta Banquet, University of Arizona. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Talk "Another Arizona" American College of Tribal Lawyers Conference, Phoenix. 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Talk at Tucson Museum of Art. 1982 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Talk "Arizona River Trails" Tucson Public Library, Green Valley. 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Talk "Books Determine" Friends of Tucson Public Library. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Talk "A Fine and Private Place" Friends of Tucson Public Library. 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Talk "Raiders of the Lost Books" University of Tulsa. 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - University of Arizona Press. 1971-1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - UCLA. 1961-1968 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "V". 1981-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "W". 1979-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Waddell, John (Pt. 1) (includes photographs). 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Waddell, John (Pt. 2) (includes photographs). 1980-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Westerners, Phoenix Corral. 1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Talk "Wildcat by the Tail" University of Arizona Foundation. 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Wilderness Calendar. 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Writers of the Purple Sage Project. 1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Writers of the Purple Sage Project. 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Writers of the Purple Sage Project. 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "X,Y,Z". 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Zamarono Club (Pt. 1). 1954-1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Zamarono Club (Pt. 2). 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Series III: University of Arizona Files, 1965-1991
  - Altman, Ellen. 1979-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Art Museum (Pt. 1). 1974-1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Art Museum (Pt. 2). 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Center for Creative Photography. 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Dickinson, Don (Pt. 1). 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Dickinson, Don (Pt. 2). 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Dickinson, Don (Pt. 3). 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Dickinson, Don (Pt. 4). 1978-1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Library Action Committee. 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Friends of the Library (Pt. 1). 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Friends of the Library (Pt. 2). 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Harvill, Richard. 1965-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Koffler, Henry. 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 1). 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 2). 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 3). 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 4). 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 5). 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Laird, David (Pt. 6). No date (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Library Christmas Display. 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Library Dedication. 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Library Survey. 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Library School. 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Library School Conference "Libraries and Scholarship". 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Library School-Hurt, Charlie. 1985-1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Nomination to Board of Regents. 1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Schaefer, John (Pt. 1). 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Schaefer, John (Pt. 2). 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Schaefer, John (Pt. 3). 1979-1985 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - UA Foundation (Pt. 1). 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - UA Foundation (Pt. 2). 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - UA Foundation (Pt. 3). 1982-1989 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Authors and Southwest Classics Files, 1890-1991
  - Abbey, Edward (Pt. 1). 1969-1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Abbey, Edward (Pt. 2). 1982-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Austin, Mary. 1920-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Austin, Mary (biography of Augusta Frank). 1973-1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Browne, J. Ross. 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Calvin, Ross. 1947-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Cather, Wilma. 1927-1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Comfort, Will Levington (Pt. 1). 1931-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Comfort, Will Levington (Pt. 2). 1971-1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Dixon, Maynard (Pt. 1). 1900-1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Dixon, Maynard (Pt. 2). 1977-1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Preface to Maynard Dixon Catalog. 1983-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Friends of the University of Arizona Library Keepsake on Maynard Dixon. 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Donation of Maynard Dixon Painting to Fresno Museum. 1950-1991 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Dobie, Frank. 1954-1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Evergreen Classics of the Arid Lands. 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Fergusson, Erna (Pt. 1). 1954-1965 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Fergusson, Erna (Pt. 2). 1970-1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Fergusson, Harvey (Pt. 1). 1934-1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fergusson, Harvey (Pt. 2). 1971-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Garvard, Lewis, and Susan Magoffin. 1856-1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Gregg, Josiah. 1967-1973 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Grey, Zane. 1922-1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Horgan, Paul (Pt. 1). No date, 1926-1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Horgan, Paul (Pt. 2). 1975-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Horgan, Paul (Pt. 3). 1981-1984 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Horgan, Paul (Pt. 4). 1985-1995 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Kino, Fr. Eusebio and Francisco Garces. 1939-1981 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Knopf, Alfred. 1966-1984 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (includes photographs). 1960-1986 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - LaFarge, Oliver (Pt. 1). 1929-1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - LaFarge, Oliver (Pt. 2). 1971-1979 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Lawrence, D.H. 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Long, Haniel. 1957-1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge (includes photographs). 1948-1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Lummis, Charles, Reprint of Some Strange Corners of Our Country. 1890-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lummis, Charles. 1922-1987 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Lummis, Charles, Biography of Lummis by Mary Sarber. 1973-1979 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Powell, John Wesley (includes photographs). 1972-1981 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Rhodes, Eugene Manlove. 1963-1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore. 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Ruxton, George (includes negatives). 1930-1973 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Santee, Ross (includes photographs). 1928-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Summerhayes, Martha (includes photographs). 1960-1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Sykes, Gordon. 1938-1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Van Dyke, John C. (Pt. 1). 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Van Dyke, John C. (Pt. 2). 1973-1989 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Van Dyke, John C., Introduction to 1976 reprint of The Desert by Arizona Historical Society. 1976-1982 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Van Dyke, John C., Article in Arizona Highways (includes photographs and negatives). 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Waters, Frank. 1964-1987 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - White, Stewart Edward (Pt. 1). 1926-1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - White, Stewart Edward (Pt. 2). 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Letters Re: "Southwest Classics Reread" Articles in Westway Magazine (Pt. 1). 1970-1974 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Letters Re: "Southwest Classics Reread" Articles in Westway Magazine (Pt. 2). 1975-1980 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Letters and Reviews re: Southwest Classics Book (Pt. 1). 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Letters and Reviews re: Southwest Classics Book (Pt. 2). 1975-1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Series V: Southwest Classics Book, 1972-1975
  - Afterword and Forword. 1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript (Pt. 1). 1973 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript (Pt. 1). 1973 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript (Pt. 1). 1973 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript (Pt. 2). 1973 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript (Pt. 2). 1973 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Photographs. No date (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Records of Ward Ritchie Press. 1972-1975 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Galleys. 1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. 1972 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Series VI: "Letters from the Southwest" Column, 1969-1980
  - Manuscripts. 1974-1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts. No date (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Articles. 1972-1980 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. 1969-1980 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Series VII: Arizona Highways, 1975-1979
  - Christmas 1976 article, manuscript draft. 1976 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Christmas 1976 article, manuscript draft. 1976 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Christmas 1976 article, manuscript draft. 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: Arizona Highways Christmas 1976 article. 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 50th Anniversary Article. 1975 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Desert Splendor Manuscript. 1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Desert Splendor manuscript. 1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Letters re: Desert Splendor. 1977-1979 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Series VIII: Photographs of the Southwest, 1975-1989
  - Ansel Adams Correspondence. 1975-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence re: Photographs of the Southwest. 1975-1981 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript Drafts, Proofs. 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript Drafts, Proofs. 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript Drafts, Proofs. 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Materials re: Photographs of the Southwest. 1976-1989 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Series IX: Where Water Flows, 1978-1981
  - Michael Collier Correspondence re: Where Water Flows, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Drafts. 1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Drafts. 1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Drafts. 1979 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Northland Press Drafts. 1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Northland Press Drafts. 1980 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Series X: River Articles and Files, 1946-1989
  - Colorado River Article in Westways Magazine. 1979 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Gila River. 1946-1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Laguna Dam (includes photographs). 1946-1966 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Little Colorado River. 1948-1978 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - New Mexico Rivers Book, Chris Condit Correspondence. 1979-1987 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Rivers Book Miscellaneous Materials (Pt. 1). 1946-1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Rivers Book Miscellaneous Materials (Pt. 2). 1946-1979 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Rivers Talk. 1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Salt River. 1948-1980 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - San Pedro River. 1970-1979 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - San Rafael and Bog Hole. 1967-1986 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Verde Essay. 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Verde Valley. 1946-1956 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Background Articles. 1946-1989 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Series XI: Arizona: A Bicentennial History, 1954-1987
  - Announcements. 1975-1987 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Letters. 1975-1985 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Gerald George Correspondence (Pt. 1). 1974-1979 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Gerald George Correspondence (Pt. 2). 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Gerald George Correspondence (Pt. 3). 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Gerald George Correspondence (Pt. 4). 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Materials Relating to Walter Bimson. 1954-1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Outline. 1972-1974 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 1). 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 2). 1974 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 3). 1974 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 4). 1974 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 5). 1974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Drafts and Notes (Pt. 6). 1974 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Miscellaneous Drafts. 1971-1976 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Completed Draft (Pt. 1). No date (Box 29, Folder 6)